*我厌倦了不名一文的快乐*
* I'm bored of cheap and cheerful *
*我只想要奢华昂贵的痛苦*
* I want expensive sadness *
*我想要让你疯狂*
* I want you to be crazy *
* 因为你正常的时候就是个傻瓜 宝贝*
* 'cause you're stupid,abcbaby when you're sane *
嗯
Yeah.
回床上来
Come back to bed.
一分钟
Gimme a minute.
给你20秒
You get 20 seconds.
嘿 你怎么了...
Hey, what are you--
女性 近30岁 强直阵挛癫痫发作
Female, late 20s,tonic clonic seizure.
癫痫持续时间?
Duration of the seizure?
差不多3分钟
A little over three minutes.
有没有癫痫病史?
Does your friend have aabchistory of epilepsy?
她从没说起过
She never said.
我是Cameron医生 你现在在医院里abc我们会照顾你的
My name is dr. Cameron. You're in aabchospital. We're gonna take care of you.
- 她的名字?abc- 不知道
- What's her name?abc- I don't know.
House
house.
我有个病例你可能会感兴趣
I have a case I think youabcmight be interested in.
不是现在
Not now.
26岁女性有过强直性癫痫大发作
A 26-year-old woman hadabca tonic clonic seizure.
我加速离开abc对你而言是"跟我聊天"的意思?
What about me speeding awayabcsays to you "let's chat"?
病史:易疲劳 两年前查出视网膜静脉闭塞
History of fatigue, and two yearsabcago she had a retinal vein occlusion.
她有糖尿病
She's diabetic.
她没有 也没有高血压病史
No, she's not. And she hasabcno history of hypertension.
这个先等等
It can wait.
我知道该准备个摄像机的 你先等着
I knew I should've set upabca video camera. Stay there.
我的天哪
Oh, my goodness.
我跟我最好的朋友搞了个恶作剧abc结果他很受伤
I played a practical joke on myabcbest friend, and he's badly injured.
多希望我能早点得到这个教训
I wish I had learned thisabcvaluable lesson earlier.
我在窗边等了一个小时 你为什么迟到了?
I was waiting by my windowabcfor an hour. Why are you late?
我在米奇餐厅跟Mercy医院的人吃早餐
I had a breakfast meeting at mickey'sabcdiner with the mercy people to tell them...
告诉他们 我回来这里上班
I'm coming back to work here.
不好意思 耽误了你废掉我的计划
Sorry if it interferedabcwith your plan to maim me.
甜甜圈真打动我心啊
Donut's a nice touch.
这是我说"欢迎回来"的方式
It's just a way ofabcsaying "welcome back."
癫痫可能是脱水或是神经方面的原因导致
The seizure could be the result ofabcdehydration or something neurological.
或者是在她体内找到的迷幻药
Or the ecstasy you found in her system.
据Hadley说abc患者是癫痫发作5小时前用的药 所以...
According to dr. Hadley, the patient took theabcdrugs about five hours before the seizure, so.
那13是怎么知道的?
What does thirteen know about it?
呃 显然她昨晚跟病人在一起
Uh, apparently she wasabcwith the patient last night.
凌晨三点的时候?
At 3:00 A.M.
欧吔
Oh, yeah.
阁楼女郎遭遇了医学秘密abc（阁楼杂志类似花花公子）
Penthouse forum meets medical mystery.
也许真的有上帝
Maybe there is a god.
空洞即逝的性爱
Empty transient sex?
自从你被诊断为亨廷顿舞蹈症abc我一直等着看你如何失控
I've been waiting for you to spiral out of controlabcever since you got your huntington's diagnosis,
但是这超乎了我的想象
but this is more than I dared hope for.
病人是由于脱水导致的癫痫发作
Patient's seizureabcresulted from dehydration,
归根到底是由于鸡尾酒和迷幻药所导致的
which resulted from a cocktailabcof alcohol and ecstasy.
- 秘密被解开了abc- 等一下
- Mystery solved.abc- Wait.
你用毒品了吗?
Were you doing drugs?
与诊断无关
Not diagnostically relevant.
取决于我们想要诊断的是什么
depends what we're trying to diagnose.
诊断你堕落得有多快
It's how steep of a spiral you're on.
我们的病人两年前就有过眼出血
Our patient hemorrhagedabcinto her eye two years ago.
同样与诊断无关abc她的视网膜静脉闭塞已经治好了
Also not diagnostically relevant.abcRetinal vein occlusion was fixed.
她的医生说只是静脉畸形
Her doctor said it was a venous anomaly.
他在那房间里吗?
is he in this room?
如果他不在 我不在乎他怎么想
Because if he's not, Iabcdon't care what he thinks.
除非他是女人 而她昨晚也在abc那我会非常关注
Unless he's a she and she was there lastabcnight too, in which case I care very deeply.
假如眼睛的问题不在静脉 而是血液呢?
What if the eye problem wasn'tabcwith her vein, but with her blood?
可以解释癫痫发作 还有为什么易疲劳
Would explain why she seized,abcwhy she's always tired.
她在派对上疯到凌晨三点 当然容易疲劳
She parties till 3:00 A.M.abcThat's why she's always tired.
但你看上去不错
Yet you seem fine.
她去年看过四个医生
She's visited four otherabcdoctors in the past year.
没有一个觉得她有病
None of them found anything.
她就是个酗酒的怀疑论者
She's a hypochondriacabcwho drank too much.
血栓可以解释一切
Blood clots could explain everything.
有点意思 骨髓活跃 血小板过多
Makes sense. Bone marrow's inabcoverdrive. Too many platelets.
不好意思
Sorry.
13 给你女朋友的骨盆扎一针去
Thirteen, go stick a needleabcin your girlfriend's pelvis.
这个不是打比方
And no, that one wasn't a metaphor.
吸点骨髓出来 这个是
Suck out some marrow. That one was.
我喜欢观赏
I like to watch.
我自己能对付的了
I can handle this alone.
你已经自己对付了
You've already handled it.
这就是为什么你需要我陪同
That's why you need a chaperone.
当然我这个陪同善解人意
Of course, I'm a very permissive,abcunderstanding chaperone.
所以别介意 忽视我的存在吧
So feel free to ignore me.
你要是很想接吻啊互摸啊洗澡啊...
You know, if you'rein the mood toabcstart kissing, or groping, or showering.
请不要跟House医生一般见识abc他老把幼稚当聪明
You'll have to excuse dr. House.abcHe mistakes immaturity for edginess.
你就是House医生?
You're dr. House?
我猜你是从昨晚呻吟声中abc知道我名字的吧
I assume my name came up lastabcnight in the form of a moan.
你性行为后出现癫痫发作
You had sex, then a seizure.
是不是特殊体位或是性爱方式导致的?
Could be a particular positionabcor activity that set it off.
听上去挺像个医学理论的 不是吗?
That sounds like aabcvalid medical theory, doesn't it?
真的很抱歉啊 忽略他就行了
I'm really sorry. Just ignore him.
你觉得我们做了什么abc我们就做了什么 并且更多
Whatever you think weabcdid,we--we did. And then some.
灯开着还是关着?
Lights on or off?
这个问题你有合理的医学解释吗?
Do you have a medicalabcrationalization for that one?
- 光敏感abc- 开着
- Light sensitivity.abc- On.
我还以为她会害羞呢
Figured she had more shame than that.
她说下流话还是含糊的用手做信号呢?
Did she talk dirty, or didabcyou rely on vague hand signals?
她挺直接让我知道她想要什么
She's, uh, prettyabcdirect about what she wants.
老生受益匪浅啊
I'm learning so much.
好啦 打个分吧 从一到十
Okay, score the score.abcScale of one to ten.
别回答
Don't answer.
7!
Seven.
终于做对了一个
Finally got one right.
就因为他吃了个甜甜圈你就要调查他?
You want to investigateabchim because he ate a donut?
他说他在米奇餐厅开了个早会
He claimed he had a morningabcmeeting at mickey's diner.
Wilson爱死米奇餐厅了
Wilson loves mickey's diner.
只要他踏进那个门他肯定要吃法式吐司堡
He has the french toast towerabcwhenever he sets foot in the door.
所以他回来工作时abc绝对不想吃碳水化合物了
There's no way he would'veabccome to work wanting more carbs.
他对我说谎了 我要知道原因
He lied to me. I need to know why.
你觉得你会发现什么?
What do you think you'll find out?
我怕他是个间谍
I'm worried that he might be a spy.
他都走了四个月了 你担心你们的友情变了
He's been gone four months. You'reabcworried the friendship has changed.
我怀疑他为裕仁天皇abc或新英格兰爱国者工作
I'm just not sure if he's working forabchirohito or the new england patriots.
你搞了个恶作剧 他没有笑
You played a practicalabcjoke on him. He didn't laugh.
我需要掌握他的把柄 谎话之类的
I need something toabclord over him, a lie--
他没有回敬你 他跟你讲道理
he didn't try toabcretaliate. He moralized.
他爱讲大道理
He always moralized.
他要讲大道理 然后讨回公道abc他还没有反击
He always moralized and gotabceven. He hasn't fired back.
万物皆变
Things always change.
那很烂
And that sucks.
是啊
Yeah.
查出他是在哪儿
Find out where he was.
早该知道这不是个巧合
should've known it wasn't a coincidence.
找到了几封你的信
Found your letters.
你认出了House的名字
You recognized house's name.
而且你是我所见过的病人之中abc唯一喜欢跟他搭讪
And you're the first patient I've seenabcwho actually enjoyed being accosted by him.
我应该告诉你的 但是...
I would'veabctold you, but--
你能跟我说什么呢?
what exactly would you have told me?
跟我上床只是为了接近House?
That you slept with me to get to house?
你为了让他接你的病例 努力了一年多?
That you've been trying to get himabcto take your case for over a year?
我病了 没有人给我回过信
I'm sick. No one even wrote back.
你利用了我
You used me.
我的动机很明确
My motives were clear.
你如果问过我名字的话abc也许就能发现我的动机
You might've figured out my motivesabcfaster if you bothered to ask my name.
我跟你去了那个酒吧abc因为我想和你谈谈
I followed you to that barabcbecause I wanted to talk to you.
看是否你能帮助我联系House
See if you'd help me get to house.
我没想到你这么主动
I didn't expect you to be so aggressive.
那个癫痫发作是真的吗?
Was that seizure even real?
我干嘛要伪装我的症状?
Why would I fake a symptom?
这只能让House更难诊治我
It would just make itabcharder for house to diagnose me.
没有什么需要诊断的 你的活检结果均正常
There's nothing to diagnose.abcYour biopsy results are negative.
那就是什么别的病
Then it's something else.
换上衣服 你得出院
Get dressed. I'm discharging you.
House收的我 显然他认为...
House admitted me.Heabcobviously thinks--
House利用你作窥探我私生活的借口
house is using you as an excuse toabcstick his nose in my personal life.
我总是觉得很累
I'm tired all the time.
我从晚上十点睡到第二天中午abc还是觉得累
Some nights I fall asleep at 10:00abcand wake up at noon,still tired.
我看过的所有医生都说我没事
Every doctor I see tellsabcme there's nothing wrong.
这说明了什么?abc他们都错了还是你错了?
And that proves what, exactly? Thatabcthey're wrong,or that you're wrong?
得了 你还指望我相信...
Oh, come on.Youabcexpect me to believe--
后仰 深呼吸 试着放松
Sit back. Deep breaths. Try and relax.
拿除颤器来 她要不行了
Get the paddles. She's gonna crash.
该死
Damn.
不得不心脏除颤以稳定病人的心脏
we had to use paddles toabcstabilize the patient's heart.
眼部问题 脑部问题 到现在的心脏问题
Eye issue, brain issue,abcnow a heart issue.
像个真正的病例
Sounds like a real case to me.
我知道了 我错了 可以继续了吗?
I get it. I was wrong. Can we move on?
你心烦意乱是因为她跟你在一起时
You're just upset because theabcwhole time she was with you,
想的却是我那很强很有力的...诊断技巧
she was thinking of my huge,abcthrobbing...diagnostic skills.
毒品可以解释所有症状
Drugs would explain everything.
今天早上你否定了毒品
This morning,you rejected drugs.
因为当时我同意13的看法 想逗她玩
That's when I thought that thirteen wasabcright and was just jerking her around.
心博骤停说明她可能毒品成瘾
Cardiac arrest means sheabccould be a serious user.
- 好极了abc- 什么?
- Great.abc- What?
这说明了她是在我家里用的药
That means that something sheabcdid at my place set this off.
要么是她带毒品来abc要么是从我药柜里拿的
Either she brought drugs in, or sheabcgrabbed something from my medicine cabinet.
也就是说我家要被搜查了
And that means myabcplace needs to be searched.
我很乐意亲自去做abc不幸的是那样House提不起兴趣
Now, I'd be happy to do that myself, but unfortunatelyabcthat would be far less titillating for house,
所以他会变着花样找原因
so he's about to come up withabcsome convoluted medical reason
让我呆在这儿 他去翻我的东西
why I have to stay here whileabche goes through my stuff.
病人的父亲刚做了旁路分流术
Patient's dad had bypass surgery.
说明她有患动脉粥样硬化的可能abc需要做个超声
Means she's a candidate forabcatherosclerosis. She needs an ultrasound.
找个借口没那么复杂
That was much lessabcconvoluted than what you just said.
我不会给你我的钥匙abc要是你非得这么做 我也要去
I'm not giving you my keys. Ifabcyou want to do this,I'm going.
谁会开锁?
Who could pick a lock?
我去
I'll go.
监督他不会偷你的内衣
Make sure he doesn't steal any underwear.
真丢黑人兄弟的脸 让开
you're a disgrace to yourabcstereotype. Move over.
你觉得你开锁比我快?
Think you can pick a lock faster than me?
不需要开锁
No need to pick.
好啊 从你的手下那里偷
Nice. Steal from your employees.
从不
Never.
我让私家侦探在调查小鸭子时弄的钥匙
I had my dick make keys whenabcI hired him to dick up the team.
总是想像她卧室里有做爱用的秋千
Always imagined she'd have aabcsex swing in the living room.
- 把我的钥匙给我abc- 我没有你的钥匙
- Give me my key.abc- Don't have your key.
你指望我相信你雇了lucas调查所有人abc除了我?
You expect me to believe that you hiredabclucas to investigate everyone except for me?
浪费钱 我早就对你了如指掌
Waste of money. I alreadyabcknow everything about you.
13有她的包 那个肯定是病人的abc检查一下毒品
Thirteen had her purse. That's gottaabcbe the patient's. Check it for drugs.
我趁机查她的卧室
I call shotgun on the bedroom.
你知道我年少时偷过车
You know that I stole aabccar when I was a teenager.
你知道我母亲有老年痴呆症
You know that my mom has alzheimer's.
其余的你一无所知
You know nothing else.
想要我调查你? 什么时候这么饥渴了?
Want me to have you investigated?abcWhen did you get so needy?
不是饥渴 只是不吃这一套
Not needy. Just don't buy it.
你总是想要知道人们的一切
You always want moreabcinformation about people.
看看你都跑到哪儿去了 包里没毒品
Look where we are. Purse is clean.
昨晚13不是第一次带陌生人回家
Last night wasn't the first time thatabcthirteen brought home some strange.
难道你找到了她的日记...
If you foundabcher diary--
没有性用具 要是你总跟一个人睡abc需要点提高性趣的配件
no toys.You sleep with the same person overabcand over, that's when you need accessories.
刚开始时 光两个人就很容易兴奋 但...
First time is plentyabcexciting on its own. Unless...
你觉得哮喘吸入器可以当性玩具吗?
you think an asthma inhalerabccould be used as a sex toy?
有很多不犯法就能了解他人的方法
There are ways of getting to knowabcpeople without committing felonies.
我对人感兴趣 对谈话不感兴趣
People interest me. Conversations don't.
因为谈话是双向的
Because conversations go both ways.
像13一样(双性恋)
like thirteen.
棕隐士蜘蛛 在你家找到的
Brown recluse. Foundabcit at your apartment.
毒液可引起痉挛和心脏问题
Their venom can cause seizuresabcand heart problems.
--除非超声波有别的发现abc--没有
- Unless the ultrasound showedabcanything-- - no.
你在哪个房间找到的?
What room did you find it in?
浴室 坐浴盆不错 很提神
bathroom. Nice bidet, byabcthe way. Very refreshing.
我没有坐浴盆
I don't have a bidet.
蜘蛛不是我找到唯一有趣的东西
Spider's not the onlyabcinteresting thing I found.
我的吸入器很棒
Yeah, my inhaler is fascinating.
配有独家昂贵网上跟踪服务
It's got its ownabcextensive online following.
你有哮喘?
You have asthma?
小的时候患过 搬进新家后复发了
When I was a kid. It started acting upabcagain when I moved into my new place.
- 你搬家了?abc- 谁在意?
- You moved?abc- Who cares?
他不在意 只是惊讶自己毫不知情
He doesn't. He's justabcsurprised he didn't know.
你保留那些别人不会特意去隐藏的事
You withhold things otherabcpeople would never bother to.
搬家 哮喘 任何你以为abc我会从口袋掏出的东西
The move,a little wheeze, whatever youabcthought was in my pocket instead of your inhaler.
也许还得去你家找找
Maybe I should make aabcreturn trip to your place.
病人身上要是没有咬痕abc找到蜘蛛也没用
Spider bite doesn't explain anything unlessabcthe patient was actually bitten by a spider.
我去检查一下
I'll do the exam.
别开玩笑 这样不合适
don't be ridiculous. Thatabcwould be inappropriate.
最好让女医生检查abc避免性吸引力坏事
It'd be better if a woman gropes her.abcThere's no sexual tension that way.
请站起来并脱掉衣服
I need you to standabcup and take off your gown.
有蜘蛛咬的话 我会感觉到
I think I would'veabcfelt a spider biting me.
不一定
Not necessarily.
经过了那晚 你还需要戴手套吗?
You really need those afterabceverything we did the other night?
那晚我不是你的医生
The other night I wasn't your doctor.
你还要生我的气多久?
How long are you gonna stay mad at me?
你还要在这呆多久?
How long are you going to be here?
好吧
Okay, then.
听着...
Look...
我本不打算再见你了
I really had no intentionabcof ever seeing you again.
那我在这 有点打破你的计划 我理解
So... having me end up here isabca little less than ideal. I get it.
但...我们才刚认识
But... we just met.
你怎么知道不想再见我了?
How'd you know you didn'tabcwant to see me again?
不是针对你个人
It's nothing personal.
我只是不喜欢重复
I'm just really not thatabcinto repeat performances.
我应该不是你第一个猎物
I figured I wasn't theabcfirst girl you cruised.
为什么这么说?
Why is that?
你很擅长此道
You're awfully good at it.
我如果经验老道的话abc会只有7分吗?
You'd think with all that experienceabcthat I'd be better than a seven.
我们刚认识 都醉得厉害
We just met. We were both drunk.
又不代表没有进步空间
Not like there wasn't potential.
我们再多练习一下 9分不在话下
Little more practice for the both ofabcus, I'd say we're looking at a nine.
轻而易举
Easy.
但这就需要不断重复了
But that would require aabcrepeat performance.
你不必把手拿开
You didn't have to move your hand.
没有啊 我手在你臀部 你感觉不到?
I didn'T. My hand's on yourabchip. You don't feel that?
没感觉 这代表什么?
No. What does that mean?
代表这不是蜘蛛咬导致的
It means it's not a spider bite.
验血证实了低钾abc解释了臀部麻木的原因
Blood test confirms low potassiumabclevels. Explains the numbness in her hip.
情况虽然不好 应该还有点时间abc给你评论一下我的个人生活
It's not good,but I think we've got time for atabcleast one or two comments about my personal life.
你却浪费在评论我的评论上了
Which you just wasted withabcthat comment about my comments.
低钾意味着心脏问题是abc由肾脏问题引起的
Low potassium means her heart problemabcwas a symptom of a kidney problem.
那肾脏问题是由什么引起的?
What caused the kidney problem?
可能是免疫球蛋白A肾病
Could be I. G. A. Nephropathy.
她没有便血
Not without blood in the urine.
那是后急性肾小球肾炎?
P. S. A. G. N. ?
但她血压正常
Not with normal blood pressure.
肾小管性酸中毒
Renal tubular acidosis.
她的肾不能过滤血液中的酸
Her kidney's don't filterabcacid out of the blood.
过量的酸降低钾含量 引发肾脏石灰化
Excess acid drives down potassium,abccauses kidney calcifications.
如果是这样abc只需碳酸氢钠中和一下酸就行了
If it's rta, all she needs isabcsodium bicarbonate for the acid
然后手术切除石灰化的部分
and surgery to removeabcthe calcifications.
给肾做个CT 看到石灰化就证实诊断了
Ct her kidneys. If you findabccalcifications, we have our diagnosis.
他现在在干嘛?
what's he doing now?
玩劫车游戏
he's playing that carjacking video game.
如果不是见红灯就停的话 能开更远
He'd get a lot farther if heabcdidn't stop at all the red lights.
也许他做了些我会嘲笑的事
Maybe he was doing somethingabche thinks I'll mock him for.
比如...所有的事
Like... just about anything.
你不这么认为
You don't think it's that.
不认为我会嘲笑他做的所有事
I don't think it's just about anything?
你不认为这只是小事
You don't think it'sabcabout anything trivial.
你要不担心 就不会坐我车里面了
If you weren't worried, youabcwouldn't be sitting in my car.
也许他在看心理医生
Maybe he's seeing a shrink.
她可不像送比萨的
that does not lookabclike a pizza delivery.
不是又怎样abcWilson才不花钱买"比萨"
doesn't matter if it isn't.abcWilson doesn't buy his pizza.
楼里住了8户
There's eight units in this building.
至少有一个像我这样反常的
There's got to be a pervert likeabcme living in at least one of them.
是呀 因为你代表这这国家八分一的人
Yes, because you represent one out ofabcevery eight people living in this country.
看来他的"比萨"口味有所开发哦
Apparently he hasabcdeveloped a taste for pizza.
世事常变啊
Ah, things change.
CT显示左肾的锥上缘还有点石灰化组织
ct shows one more calcification nearabcthe superior pyramid on the left kidney.
看到了
See it.
你不想House在你家发现的东西
That, um, thing you were hopingabchouse didn't find at your place.
被我找到了
I, uh, I found it.
两星期前他做了CAG序列检测
He did the cag test two weeks ago.
数值这么高意味着abc你剩下的时间比意料中少了
A number this high means youabchave less time than you thought.
不开心是可理解的
It's understandable you'd be upset.
但不代表你要自暴自弃
Doesn't mean you have to self-destruct.
如果你打算评判我abc那么从House手里把我救下也不算高尚
It's not noble for you to protect meabcfrom house if you're just gonna judge--
有些事你应该要去做
there are things you should be doing.
锻炼 改善平衡和协调
Working out, improvingabcbalance and coordination.
是啊 听上去好令人兴奋哦
Yeah, that sounds like a blast.
我现在很开心
I'm having fun.
尽可能充实我的人生
Cramming as muchabclife into my life as I can.
你嗑药 熬夜 跟陌生人做爱
You're doing drugs. Staying up allabcnight,having sex with strangers.
我觉得这样挺开心 晚安
It sounds fun to me. Good night.
缝合切口
Close the incisions.
她甚至都不会留下疤痕
She won't even have a scar.
含氧量在下降
Her o2 stats are dropping.
你割到什么了?
Did you nick something?
手术很利落 血压很稳定
Procedure was clean. Bp's strong.
她没有呼吸 需要插管
Well, she's not breathing.abcWe need to intubate.
治好肾后呼吸就出问题了
the breathing problem startedabcafter we fixed her kidney problem.
意味着肾小管性酸中毒不是根本问题
Means the rta isn't the underlying cause.
13去哪了?
Where's thirteen?
塞车严重 她可能只是--
Traffic's bad.abcShe's probably just--
不在这
not here.
不是肺的问题
it's not her lungs.
无肿块 无渗漏
No masses, no infiltrates.
肺没事 但她还是不能呼吸
Lungs are working,butabcshe still can't breathe.
没进货的供应站无法供货
Distribution plant can't distributeabcif it's not getting deliveries.
如果肺没事 也许问题出在补给线abc气管萎陷
If her lungs are fine, maybe theabcproblem's in the supply line. Airway collapse.
那根本原因就是abc自身免疫或者营养失调之类的
That could signal autoimmune or someabckind of dystrophy as the underlying cause.
只有一个办法弄清楚是否气管的问题
There's only one way to findabcout if her air way failed.
让它再发生一次
Make it happen again.
让13的女友去踏车
Stick thirteen's carpetabccleaner on a treadmill.
支气管激发试验
Methacholine challenge.
去把13找回来
And someone find the carpet.
检测中 15分钟后完毕
Exam going on. 15 minutes.
早上好 Hadley医生
Good morning,dr. Hadley.
刚跟我兄弟聊过了
Just spoke to my brother.
你指是兄弟是?
And by brother,you mean?
我父母的另一个儿子
I mean my parents'other son.
只有父亲是相同的
Same dad.
他上星期接到你私家侦探的电话 你说谎了
Got a call last week fromabcyour P.I. You lied.
你还是调查过我了
You did have me investigated.
你就你所知奚落团队中每一个abc却把我落下
You've been taunting the team with whatabcyou've learned, but you never came after me.
是因为你根本没查到可利用的
Means you couldn't find anything.
说的对
You're right.
那是因为自从17岁以后
That's because you haven't doneabcanything stupid, spontaneous,
你都没做过任何愚蠢abc孩子气或稍微有趣的事
or even vaguelyabcinteresting since you were 17.
真惹人伤心
And that's just sad.
我抓到她在门诊室静脉输液
I found her in the clinicabcgiving herself iv fluids.
至少让她输完啊 看着真残
at least you could've let herabcfinish. She looks terrible.
手腕上夜总会印章还是新的
she has a fresh night clubabcstamp on her wrist.
她不适合行医了
She's in no condition to practice.
除非这是惩罚游戏的序曲abc否则叫我来有--
Unless this is a prelude to an actualabcspanking, there's no reason for me to be--
我想让她接受药检
I want her to take a drug test.
你不能强迫我接受
You can't make me do that.
但我可以暂停你的工作abc直到你接受为止
But I can suspend youuntil you do.
就因为她下班时间去夜总会了?
Because she went to aabcnightclub in her free time?
还是因为她下班时间去做爱了?
Or because she had sex in her free time?
病人按酸中毒进行常规治疗
Patient was undergoing routineabcsurgery for rta.
不需要13在这看着
Didn't need thirteen here for that.
也不需要你让我的雇员去打卡或验尿
And I don't need you making myabcemployees punch a clockor pee in a cup.
我们走
Let's go. Come on.
谢谢
Thank you.
顺道说说 手术不算常规
By the way, the surgery was not routine.
病人停止呼吸了 你没参加讨论
Patient stopped breathingabcand you missed a differential.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
什么? 你刚刚才维护了我
What? You just defended me.
不 我只是帮你逃过药检了
No, I just preventedabcyou from getting a drug test.
也许拯救了你的职业生涯
Probably saved your career.
一个瘾君子医生够我受的了
I'm already taking responsibilityabcfor one doctor with a drug habit.
我没有上瘾
I don't have a drug habit.
淫荡的派对女孩很有趣abc等她吐在你鞋子上
The slutty party girl is funabctill she pukeson your shoes.
就变成了肉中刺了
Then she's just a pain in the ass.
好几个月没坐过这沙发
I haven't sat on thisabccouch for four months.
它还记得我的屁股
It remembers my cheeks.
- 我好怀念abc- 我也是
- I miss this.abc- Me too.
我试图工作 你来打搅
Me trying to work. You interrupting.
你的病人能等5分钟 我们叙叙旧
Oh, come on. Your patients couldabcwait five minutes. Get me caught up.
你做了什么? 旅行了?abc有了新的爱好?
Come on,what did you do?abcTravel? Did you get a new hobby?
- 跟谁交往了?abc- 事实上是的
- Did you meet someone?abc- Actually, yes.
我开始约会了
I sort of started dating someone.
棒极了 她是做什么的?
Great. What does she do?
是个演员?
Is she... an actress?
不是 为什么你会这么想?
No. Why would you think that?
我以为你想找点刺激的
I just figured you'd wantabcsomething a little more... exciting.
她不是...
She's not...
你迟早会知道的 因为你会跟她见面
you're gonna find out anywayabcbecause you're gonna meet her.
她是个妓女
She'S... a prostitute.
曾是
Used to be.
犯过错
She made some mistakes.
单身母亲 有吸毒史
Single mom,had some drug issues.
但... 她很聪明
But... she's so smart.
她想上法学院...
She wants to go to law school. And...
我答应帮她付学费
I told her I'd help her with tuition.
你认识她多久?
How long have you known her?
我就知道你会这样
Oh, I knew you'd be like this.
- 我只是问个问题abc- House...
- I asked a question.abc- House...
你自己嗑药又召妓abc没资格评判人家
you are a drug addict. You go toabcprostitutes. You can't be judgmental.
可是
And yet.
别这样
Please, don't do this to me.
我很伤心 我想开心点
I was hurting,and I wanted to feel good.
我没想到会发展成这样的...
I didn't expect it to go this way. I...
Amber... 说希望我向前看
amber... said that sheabcwanted me to move on.
她想我...
That she wanted me to...
快乐 而...
be happy. And...
Debbie能令我快乐
debbie makes me happy.
你快乐 我就...
If you're happy, I'm...
我听说了
I heard.
是的 我在找转机
Yeah. I'm looking for my ticket back.
如果我使你不开心了我道歉
Sorry if I upset you.
- 我不想侵犯你的隐私abc- 不是你的错
- I didn't want to invade your privacy.abc- It wasn't your fault.
能告诉我诊断进展么?
Can you get me caught up?
你觉得你能发现abc我们发现不了的东西?
Think you're gonnaabcfind something we didn't?
我这么做为了病人 也为了我自己
It's good for the patient. Good for me.
X光显示肺部没问题abc排除了肺动脉高血压
Films are clean. Weabcruled out hypertension.
在跑步机上做支气管激发试验
Guys have her on a treadmillabcrunning a methacholine challenge.
还有 你的行为太愚蠢了
And I still think you'veabcbeen acting like an idiot.
我知道
I know.
你们有没发现 似乎肺部有点暗?
Did you talk about whether thisabclung field looks a little dark?
可能只是曝光过度
It's probably just over-exposed.
或者是横膈膜扁平
Or her diaphragm's a little flat.
肺部过度膨胀的征兆
Could be a sign of hyper inflation.
表明出现了肺阻塞
Suggests a pulmonary obstruction.
肺囊肿
Lung cysts.
X光片上看不出来
They wouldn't show upon an x-ray.
跑步机测试不会使她呼吸道闭合abc只会让她的肺爆炸
Treadmill test isn't gonna close herabcairway. It'll make her lungs explode.
喉咙没问题
Her throat's fine.
我想让呼吸道塌陷 它却没有
We made her airway collapse,abcbut it's not collapsed.
囊肿破裂! 她的肺塌陷了
You ruptured a cyst! Her lung collapsed.
两边肺都有罗音
Breath sounds on both sides.
让开
Move.
支气管移到了左边
Trachea's deviating to the left.
做得好
Nice.
胸部CT证实是多发性肺囊肿abc其中一个囊肿在测试时破裂
Chest ct confirmed multiple lung cysts, oneabcof which burst during the treadmill test.
幸而13发现问题所在abc并使肺部重新充气
Luckily, thirteen figured out the problemabcand was there to re-inflate her lung.
肺囊肿加上其他症状指向淀粉样变性病abc是能治疗的
lung cysts plus all her other symptomsabccould be amyloidosis, which we can manage.
- 或者是肺纤维化--abc- 谢谢
- Or pulmonary fibrosisabcwhich-- - thank you.
下面可以由我的人接手了
My employees canabctake care of it from here.
要对囊肿进行活检
We need to biopsy the cysts.
你开除我 是因为我一团糟
You fired me because I screwed up.
但我证明我可以胜任工作
I just proved I can pull my weight.
你只证明你会在病人胸口扎洞
All you proved is youabcknow how to make an entrance.
House 你应该多给她一次机会abc她发现了囊肿 救了病人一命
house, she deserves another shot.abcShe found the cysts,saved the patient.
如果13在鉴别诊断时现身abc病人根本不需要人救命
Who wouldn't have needed saving if thirteen hadabcshown up at the differential in the first place.
让她回来工作 House
Give her her job back, house.
不然呢? 你辞职走人?
Or what? You're gonna quit?
去做活检
Go do the biopsy.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你还要我说多少遍?
How much clearer do I need to make this?
这演的是哪一出 "和妓女约会"?
What does that evenabcmean,"dating a hooker"?
他是个有"弥赛亚情结"的笨蛋
He's an idiot with a messiah complex.
妄想拯救所有人abc所以他第一个老婆有根木头假肢
Savior to all who need saving. That'sabcwhy his first wife had a wooden leg.
第二个老婆是加拿大人
Second wife was canadian.
- 他才是需要拯救的人abc- 被你还是被妓女?
- He's the one who needs to be saved.abc- From you or the ho?
妓女看中的是他的钱
The ho's just using him for his money.
慢 这么说不好abc(House常向Wilson借钱)
Wait. Bad example.
通常这种情况 我会跟踪那女的
Normally in these situations,abcI'd follow the girl,
好抓住她的把柄向他报告
find out somethingabcembarrassing about her to show him.
这项不用劳神做了
But since that's our starting position...
直接打断她腿得了
proceed directly to the leg-breaking.
我不会打断她的腿abc说不定有皮条客罩她
I'm not breaking her legs.abcShe probably has a pimp.
至少有个哥哥 或弟弟abc或溺爱她的姐姐
Or, at least,an older brother. Or aabcyounger brother. Or over protective sister.
查她 查她全家 查她客户
Find her, find her family,abcfind client number nine.
反正找出什么可以逼她放手的
Just get me something I canabcuse to force her to back off.
抱歉打扰你们开会 Mannixabc(60年代电视剧侦探)
Sorry to interrupt your meeting, mannix.
这是肺活检的结果
Here's the result from the lung biopsy.
干嘛不找男的?
Why not men?
你是双性恋
You're bisexual.
要是你想自我毁灭abc大可以和男的乱搞
If you were just being self-destructive,abcyou'd be having random sex with men.
遭到虐打 染上性病的机会更大
Better chance of gettingabcassaulted, catching a disease.
要是纯粹想上床 找个男的更顺手
If this were just about getting laid,abcit'd be a lot easier to pick up men.
或者丑女人
Or ugly girls.
那女的很正点
This woman's hot.
就是说你喜欢挑战 喜欢征服
Which means you like theabcchallenge, the conquest.
控制让你兴奋
It's the control that gets you off.
控制了女人让你以为可以abc控制自己的命运
And controlling women is as close as you canabcget to controlling what's gonna happen to you.
我还以为我只是喜欢胸脯
Here I thought I was just into boobs.
与其和陌生人纠缠
Instead of gettingabcsweaty with a stranger,
何不挑战更高级别?
why don't you try takingabcit to the next level?
扮演上帝
Play god.
告诉她 她只有几年好活了
Tell a girl that she'sabcgotten years to live.
她得了淋巴管肌瘤病
She has lam.
好吧
Okay.
这不是一项考验
This is not a test.
即便你成功了也不能归队--
You're not getting yourabcjob back if you can--
我知道听到自己的死期是什么感受
I know what it's like to get this news,
由你说出来只会让人更难受
and no one should haveabcto get it from you.
肺囊肿活检发现平滑肌细胞
The biopsy of your lung cystabcshowed smooth muscle cells.
表示你可能得了淋巴管肌瘤病
That's indicative ofabca disease called lam.
那你们要怎么治?
What do you do for that?
手术切除囊肿
Surgery to remove the cysts.
但...会复发
But... they'll come back.
囊肿会逐渐取代肺组织abc你的肺将停止运作
Little by little, the cysts replace healthyabclung tissue until your lungs stop working.
我会死
I'm gonna die.
是的
Yes.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
他们会尽可能切除所有囊肿
they removed all the cysts they could.
应该能让你的呼吸好转
That should help you breathe better.
囊肿隔多久会复发?
How long until the cysts come back?
不能确切预计 对不起
We don't know exactly. I'm sorry.
不要再说对不起了
Stop saying you're sorry.
我知道你很害怕
I know you're scared.
我不知道自己是什么感觉
I don't know what I feel.
头几天你脑子会一片麻木
You're gonna be numbfor a few more days.
你会回家哭上几个星期
Then you'll go home andabccry for a few weeks.
然后你会感到愤怒
And then you get angry.
告诉自己 一切都不要紧了
Start telling yourself nothingabcmatters anymore.
你开始做蠢事
You start doing stupid things.
也许会去酒吧钓女人
Maybe you go out to barsabcand pick up a bunch of women.
你...
You're...
你还能活多久?
how long do you have?
也许比你长点 也许短点
Maybe a little more thanabcyou. Maybe a little less.
我和你赛跑
I'll race you.
我会再来看你
I was thinking maybe I'd come back later.
好的
Sounds good.
上帝 怎么回事?
Oh, god. What's going on?
全部血球细胞数下降abc出现新症状 是再生性贫血
All her blood counts are down.abcIt's a new symptom. Aplastic anemia.
难道"开除"一词有别的解释我不知道?
Does the word "fired" have some whole otherabcdefinition that I'm not aware of?
我不是为你工作abc好 不用给我发工钱
I don't work for you.abcFine. Don't pay me.
只要让我完成这个病例
Just let me finish out this case.
她快死了 你倒爱上她了
So you like her now that she's dying.
要是她不用死了呢?
What happens if she stops dying?
别纠结这个了
there's no danger of that right now.
如果我们不能找出真正病因abc她只能活几天 而不是几年
If we don't figure out what's wrongabcwith her, she's got days,not years.
再生性贫血排除了淋巴管肌瘤病
aplastic anemia takes lam off the table.
不幸的是 其余选项也好不到哪去
Unfortunately, none of ourabcother choices are any better.
假设是PNH(阵发性睡眠性血红蛋白尿)abc外加呼吸道感染
Pnh with some sort ofabcrespiratory infection.
最多能活12年
Best case gives her 12 years.
- 快的有Langerhans细胞增生症abc- 只有几个月
- Or fast-movingabclangerhans. - A few months.
或者是肥大细胞增生症abc会导致全身性休克 几天内可致命
Or mastocytosis,which can causeabcsystemic shock and kill her in days.
去吧 测试所有的病 没你的份
Go. Test for everything. Not you.
你只是来探病的
You're just a visitor.
你的病人怎样了?
How's your patient?
- 不是Langerhans细胞增生abc- 很好
- She doesn't have langerhans.abc- That's good.
相对而言 诊断出癌症就算是好消息了
Actually, a cancer diagnosisabcwould be good news right now.
你觉得...我这人闷吗?
Do you think... I'm boring?
闷
Yes.
- 你是在敷衍我abc- 没错
- You're saying that just to screw with me.abc- Yeah.
为什么你指望有别的答案?
Why would you expect anything else?
我料到House操纵我
I expect house to pull my strings.
我料到Cameron让我好过点
I expect cameron to make me feel better.
我指望新团队听我使唤
I expect the new team to kiss my ass.
还有我指望你说老实话abc因为你从不扯淡
And I expect you to be honest,abc'cause you don't give a crap.
是的 你这人很闷蛋 这番话很闷蛋
Yes, you're boring.abcThat speech was boring.
谢了
Thanks so much.
你从不让别人的问题影响你
You don't let otherabcpeople'sproblems affect you.
也不让你的问题影响自己
You don't let your ownabcproblems affect you.
但恰恰是错误让人变得有趣
And it's the screw-ups thatabcmake us interesting.
你从不失去控制abc这敢情好 但...太闷了
You're never out of control.abcWhich is good, and... boring.
不失去控制 意味着你从不会豁出去
Never losing control also means you'reabcnever putting yourself out there.
不会挑战极限
Never pushing your limits.
话虽如此 你却有个文身 所以...
On the other hand, youabcdo have a tattoo, so...
也许我错了
maybe I'm wrong.
* 哈利路亚 驻足凝视 *
* Hallelujah stop and stare *
* 基督耶稣的眷顾让我们 *
* when will jesusabcfind us here could we *
* 得以生存 *
* survive *
* 你何以自诩知晓 *
* how can you pretend to know *
* 你是谁或去往何方 *
* who you are or where you will go *
* 你只是匆匆过客 *
* when you just get by *
* 织梦啊 直至时光 *
* and dream dreaming all the time *
* 消逝 *
* away *
很高兴你陪着我
I'm glad you're here.*
* 织梦啊 直至年华 *
* And dream dreaming all your time *
* 老去 *
* away *
她需要骨髓移植
she needs a bone marrow transplant.
有测试结果了?abc哪种病呈阳性反映?
Test results are back?abcWhat's she positive for?
没有 但找到了匹配的捐赠者
Nothing. But we've got a donor match.
没找到病因就直接做骨髓移植--
Jumping to a transplantabcwhen we don't know what she--
我知道她有血液疾病
I know she has a blood disorder.
如果是PNH 她需要骨髓移植abc如果是白血病
Could be pnh. She needs a boneabcmarrow transplant. Or leukemia.
她需要骨髓移植abc如果是地中海贫血症
She needs a bone marrowabctransplant. Or thalassemia.
- 还是需要骨髓--abc- 行 我明白了
- She needs a boneabcmarrow-- - yeah, I get it.
但她的状况根本支持不了全身放疗
But she'll never surviveabctotal body irradiation.
所以我们不做放疗
So we don't radiate her.
她的骨髓几乎清除殆尽了abc血白细胞数接近零
Her marrow's nearly wipedabcoutalready. Counts almost zero.
"几乎"不代表没有
"Almost" being the key word.
新骨髓会攻击老骨髓abc她会因移植物抗宿主病死去
The new marrow would attack the oldabcmarrow. She'll die from graft-versus-host.
你有更好的办法么?
You got a better idea?
她信任你 让她签同意书
She trusts you. Go get her consent.
有些事情还是不知道的好
Sometimes I find outabcthings you'd rather not know.
从他垃圾箱里找到的
This was in his trash.
他在吸毒
He's using.
你回归了
You're back.
聪明
Genius.
见鬼 我就知道演得太过了
Damn. I knew the fake works was too much.
你别无选择
Well, you had no choice.
冒牌妓女女朋友后abc还能有啥狠招?
Where were you gonna goabcafter fake hooker girlfriend?
你怎么知道我们在外头?
How did you knowhe was outside?
拐杖痕
Cane prints.
实话说 我有点受到侮辱
I'm actually kind of insulted.
吸毒固然骗不了你abc但你居然相信我爱上了一个妓女?
No way I'm a drug addict, but you completelyabcbuy that I fell in love with a prostitute?
你表演得很卖力
You played to your strengths.
确切来说 你利用了你的弱点来演
By which I mean youabcplayed to your weaknesses.
上帝
Oh, my god.
你居然搬出死鬼女友来给我下套
You invoked yourabcdead girlfriend's name to sell me.
我太崇拜你了
You're my hero.
这辈子最值的30美元
Best $30 I ever spent.
才30? 你还留着她电话不?
It's 30? Did you keep her number?
真不走运 我杀了她 埋在地下室
Unfortunately, I killed herabcand buried her in the basement.
可惜
Shame.
- 饿了么?abc- 嗯
- Hungry?abc- Yeah.
那么 说真的
So, seriously.
那天一早你去哪儿了?
Where were you the other morning?
老天 不要再逼我了
Ugh, don't make me do this again.
跟你一点关系也没有
It has nothing to do with you.
那告诉我嘛
Then tell me.
我们星期一打保龄
We're going bowling on monday.
这周末我去你家打扑克
I'm coming over toabcplay poker this weekend.
一切还是老样子 你得相信
Nothing's changed.abcYou have to trust that.
好吧
Okay.
你还是会继续跟踪我 对吧?
You're gonna keepabcfollowing me,aren't you?
我们一直都这么做
It's what we do.
今晚八点候在我家里门口
Be outside my apartment at 8:00 tonight.
- 她同意骨髓移植abc- 很好
- She said yes to the transplant.abc- Good.
你已经陷入了毁灭的漩涡
You're in a downwardabcspiral of destruction.
我可以停下
I can stop.
你只会越陷越深
You're gonna keep spiraling.
不停地惹乱子
Keep screwing around.
把试图帮你的人都赶走abc直到没人再愿意帮你
Keep slashing away at every person who triesabcto help until no one tries to help anymore.
直到坠落谷底 直到生命尽头
Till you hit bottom. Till you're dead.
在那之前 你还能为我所用
Until then... I can use you.
让我回来工作?
You're hiring me back?
你做得不错
You did good work.
我昨天也做得不错 但还是被炒了abc有什么不一样?
I did good work yesterday, andabcI was still fired. What changed?
你是想让我花时间陪着她
You wanted me to spend time with her.
看我和她病情有没有关系
See if I could still make a connection.
只是与你诊断有关 并不是对她产生感情
You connected with aabcdiagnosis,not with her.
你是想要救我 想要控制我
You're trying to saveabcme, trying to control me.
你只是在做你认为...
You're doing exactlyabcwhat you think--
开裂了
cracks.
你的嘴唇开裂了
You're lips are cracked.
你最近用吸入器了吗?
You been using your inhaler lately?
过敏而已 别转移话题 你总是这样
Allergies. Don't deflect.abcYou always deflect.
她哭了吗?
Did she cry?
你说她要死了的时候 她哭了吗?
When you told her that sheabcwas gonna die, did she cry?
她很难过 她...
She... gotabcupset.She--
她流泪了吗?
were there tears?
没有
No.
切开洋葱 会释放出合丙烷硫醛的薄雾
Chopping an onion releases aabcmist of syn-propanethial-s-oxide,
这种刺激物会让人产生一种反应
a chemical irritant which causes peopleabcto have a very predictable reaction.
她没眼泪
She has no tears.
要么是这教人伤心abc要么是看了"Brian's Song"
It was either this orabcput on brian's song.
我没时间去Wilson家了
I didn't have time to stop by wilson's.
她得的是干燥综合症
She has sjogren's.
分泌眼泪和唾液的腺体受到了损伤
It attacks the glands thatabcproduce tears and saliva.
也引发了肺囊肿和肾小管酸中毒
Also, by the way, causesabclung cysts and rta.
但不会引发出血
It doesn't cause bleeding.
就像你同男人
It's like you and men.
你不经常这么做 并不意味着你不能
Just 'cause you usuallyabcdon't, doesn't mean you can't.
这不会导致其他人唇裂
And it doesn't cause crackedabclips in other people.
唾液的缺乏使她的嘴成了真菌的滋生地
Lack of spit makes her mouth a breedingabcgroundfor a fungus like candida.
哮喘吸入器让你的嘴也不设防
Your asthma inhaler did the same for you.
口腔中的免疫系统被摧毁了
Wiped out your mouth's immune system.
那就是说 她也得了我的病
So she's got what I've got.
只是机会性感染abc根本性病因不会传染
Just the opportunistic infection,abcnot the underlying condition.
搞拉拉还真是救人无数啊
Another life saved byabcgirl-on-girl action.
我会没事吗?
I'm gonna be okay?
你会好起来的
You're gonna be okay.
甲强龙可以有效控制干燥综合症
Methylprednisolone to getabcthe sjogren's under control.
再来点人造眼泪 加强此刻的视觉效果
And some artificial tears to maximizeabcthe visual impact of this moment.
Spencer会好起来的
Spencer's gonna be fine.
听说你复职了
And I hear you got your job back.
你要是不开口 我就一直站在这
I'm gonna keep standingabchere until you say something.
我感觉孤立无援
I feel alone.
她跟我不同
And she hasn't gone anywhere.
她能活
She gets to live.
我想回家 我累了
I'm gonna go home. I'm tired.
你觉得如何?
What do you think?
哦 我的天啊!
Oh, my god!
你们也常来这买东西?
You guys shop here too?
这里有普林斯顿奶嘴之王
Best nipples in princeton.
你来这干嘛?
Why are you here?
因为他吃了那个甜甜圈
Because he ate the donut.
我实在很抱歉 他肯定跟踪我来着
I'm so sorry. He must've followed me.
毫无疑问
I'm sure.
你显然没有怀孕 所以要么是买来当礼物
Well, you're clearly not pregnant, soabceither you're buying this as a gift,
要么是某种诡异的期望abc"精诚所至 金石为开"
or this is some kind of weird "ifabcyou build it,they will come" moment.
我要领养一个孩子
I'm adopting a baby.
她要我做推荐人abc那天早上就是在忙这件事
She asked me to be a character reference.abcThat's where I was the other morning.
很抱歉 我不能辜负她的信任
I'm sorry. I couldn'tabcbetray her confidence.
在批准前 我不想让别人知道
I didn't want anyone else to knowabcin case I didn't get approved.
今天 我得到批准了
Today, I did.
* 黑暗之路 *
* It's a dark road
* 黑暗之路 带我回家 *
* and a dark way thatabcleads to my house *
* 人们都说 *
* and the word says *
* 我之于你 终将无迹可寻 *
* you're never gonnaabcfind me there oh no *
你不祝贺我吗?
are you gonna congratulate me?
你快乐 我就...
If you're happy, I'm...
* 你我之间 天意使然 *
* it didn't get there by itself *
* 有一种感觉 *
* There's a feeling *
* 你从未曾感受 *
* but you're not feeling it at all *
* 有一种意义 *
* there's a meaning *
* 你再无法倾听... *
* but you're not listening anymore...*